[柯克]舰长日志，星历5928.5
[KIRK] Captain's log, stardate 5928.5.
企业号收到了来自加缪二上一群科学家的求救信号
The Enterprise has received a distress call from a group of scientists on Camus II,
他们正在探索一个死亡文明的废墟
who are exploring the ruins of a dead civilization.
他们的处境很绝望
Their situation is desperate.
其中两名幸存者是探险队外科医生科尔曼
Two of the survivors are the expedition surgeon, Doctor Coleman,
和探险队队长珍妮丝·莱斯特博士
and the leader of the expedition, Dr. Janice Lester.
她怎么了？
What's wrong with her?
暴露于辐射
Exposure to radiation.
那是什么形式的辐射？
What form of radiation was it?
我从来没有遇到过的
Nothing I've ever encountered.
珍妮丝你必须保持绝对平静
Janice, you must remain absolutely quiet.
那是医生的命令，不是我的
Those are doctor's orders, not mine.
舰长，三录仪采集到微弱的生命读数
Captain. Tricorder picking up very faint life readings.
距离这里大约700米
Approximately seven hundred metres from here.
必须立即提供帮助
Help will have to be immediate.
[呻吟]
[GROANS]
也许你在场能让她平静下来
Perhaps your presence will quiet her.
我希望过我不再见到你
I hoped I wouldn't see you again.
我不怪你
I don't blame you.
我们一起在星际舰队的那一年是我生命中唯一鲜活的时光
The year we were together at Starfleet is the only time in my life I was alive.
我从来没有阻止过你继续你的太空工作
I never stopped you from going on with your space work.
你的星舰舰长的世界不接受女性
Your world of starship captains doesn't admit women.
这不公平
It isn't fair.
是不公平
No, it isn't.
你因此惩罚和折磨我
And you punished and tortured me because of it.
我爱过你
I loved you.
我们本可以在群星之间漫游
We could have roamed among the stars.
我们会互相残杀
We'd have killed each other.
那可能更好了
It might have been better.
[柯克]宇宙，最后的边疆
[KIRK] Space, the final frontier.
这些是星舰企业号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务：探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
寻找新生命和新文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇踏前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
星际旅行：原初
第三季第二十四集
你有过机会，柯克舰长
You had your chance, Captain Kirk.
你应该杀了我
You should've smothered the life in me.
然后人们会说：“珍妮丝·莱斯特博士
Then they would have said, "Dr. Janice Lester
在执行任务时死于辐射中毒”
died of radiation poisoning in the line of duty."
你为什么不做？你一直想，不是吗？
Why didn't you do it? You always wanted to, didn't you?
你有力气去做
You had the strength to do it.
但是你害怕
But you were afraid.
你总是害怕
You were always afraid.
现在珍妮丝·莱斯特取代了柯克舰长的位置
Now Janice Lester takes the place of Captain Kirk.
我已经拥有了你的力气
I already possess your physical strength.
只是这个柯克舰长不怕杀人
Only this Captain Kirk is not afraid to kill.
[呻吟]
[MOANS]
现在你知道身为一个女人的羞辱感了
Now you know the indignity of being a woman.
对你来说，这种痛苦很快就会过去，就像对我一样
For you this agony will soon pass, as it has for me.
安静！安静！
Quiet! Quiet!
相信我，死总比独自活在女人的身体里好
Believe me, it is better to be dead than to live alone in the body of a woman.
死了更好
It's better to be dead.
[脚步声]
[FOOTSTEPS]
麦考伊医生，你的报告
Doctor McCoy. Your report.
我们太晚了，吉姆，什么也做不了
We were too late, Jim. There's nothing could be done.
是所说的辐射吗？
Was it radiation as suggested?
不，我认为是鏼
No, I believe it was celebium.
但是，科尔曼医生不同意
However, Doctor Coleman disagrees.
具体一点很重要
To be specific is essential
因为鏼的治疗相当…
because the treatment of celebium is quite ...
麦考伊医生
Doctor McCoy.
我们不在的时候你有没有注意到任何不寻常的症状？
Did you notice any unusual symptoms while we were gone?
不，完全没有，她一直都昏迷不醒
No, nothing at all. She was unconscious all of the time.
莱斯特博士快死了
Dr. Lester is near death.
也许发生在她员工身上的事给她造成的打击也是一部分原因
Perhaps the shock of knowing what happened to her staff is part of her problem.
我肯定是的
I'm sure it is.
把她传送到企业号要比等待安全
Beaming her up to the Enterprise will be less harmful than waiting.
我不知道，我不确定
I don't know. I'm not sure.
柯克舰长呼叫企业号
Captain Kirk to the Enterprise.
我是斯科特，长官
Mr. Scott, sir.
斯科特先生
Mr. Scott.
准备将登陆小队传送上船
Prepare to beam the landing party aboard
还有另外两人，其中一个病危
plus two others. One critically ill.
让医疗团队随时待命接收患者
Have a medical team standing by to receive the patient.
通话完毕
Captain Kirk, out.
准备传送上船
Prepare to beam aboard.
科尔曼医生，陪病人去医务室
Docotr Coleman, accompany the patient to the Sickbay.
史波克先生，让飞船脱离轨道
Mr. Spock, take the ship out of orbit.
恢复指定航线
Resume designated course.
麦考伊医生
Doctor McCoy.
麦考伊医生你和科尔曼医生似乎对诊断意见不一
Docotr McCoy, you and Docotr Coleman seem to disagree on diagnosis.
不，不完全相左，我们都同意这是辐射
No, not entirely. We both agree it's radiation.
科尔曼医生不准备说什么形式的辐射
Docotr Coleman isn't prepared to say what form of radiation.
会影响你完成正确的治疗吗？
Will it affect your arriving at a correct treatment?
这很关键
It's crucial.
嗯，这对我来说尤其令人不安
Well, this is especially disturbing to me
因为…个人原因
for ... personal reasons.
哦？我不知道你和她那么熟
Oh? I didn't know you knew her that well.
哦，是的，我已经很久没有见到她了
Oh, yes. It's been a long time since I saw her.
当关系变得认真起来时，我离开了她
I walked out on her when it became serious.
嗯，那时你一定很年轻，吉姆
Well, you must have been very young at the time, Jim.
年轻不是每件事的借口，麦考伊医生
Youth doesn't excuse everything, Doctor McCoy.
对我来说是非常不愉快的记忆
It's a very unhappy memory for me.
我没有意识到这一点
I didn't realize that.
我会尽我所能
I shall do everything in my power.
谢谢，非常感谢
Thank you. Thank you very much.
莱斯特博士…能逃脱真是一个非常幸运的年轻人
Dr. Lester ... is certainly a very lucky young person to have escaped.
是的，很幸运，非常幸运
Yes, very lucky. Very lucky.
[呻吟]
[GROANS]
刚刚开始
It just began.
那你最好停下来
Well you'd better put a stop to it!
如果你让莱斯特博士完全恢复意识
If you allow Dr. Lester to become fully conscious,
她就会知道发生了什么
she'll know what has happened.
可能没有人会相信
Probably no one will believe it.
可能？
Probably?
这就是我们能要求的一切
That's all we can ask for.
现在如何解释死亡？
How can death be explained now?
我告诉你不能继续了
I tell you it can't continue.
你杀死了每一个工作人员
You killed every one of the staff.
你把他们派到了你明知鏼护盾薄弱的地方
You sent them where you knew the celebium shielding was weak.
现在你为什么不杀了他？你有过绝佳的机会
Now why didn't you kill him? You had the perfect opportunity.
时间不够
There wasn't enough time.
我给足了你要的时间
I gave you every minute you asked for.
他太执着于生活，我不能…
He hung onto life too hard. I couldn't ...
你不能，因为你爱他
You couldn't because you love him.
你想让我成为杀他的凶手
You want me to be his murderer.
爱？他？
Love？Him?
我爱他拥有的生活
I love the life he led.
星舰指挥官的权力
The power of a starship commander.
现在是我的生活了
It's my life now.
我不会成为杀人犯
I won't become a murderer.
你就是凶手！
You are a murderer!
你知道是鏼，你本可以治疗他们
You knew it was celebium. You could've treated them for it.
你杀了好多次人了
You're a murderer many times over.
吉姆，你在这里做什么？
Jim, what are you doing here?
我以为我在场可以让莱斯特医生平静下来
I thought my presence might quiet Dr. Lester.
它似乎产生了相反的效果
It seems to have had the opposite effect.
跟你没关系
It's nothing to do with you.
这是发展中的放射病的症状
It's a symptom of the developing radiation illness.
船上设备的测试表明没有内部辐射损伤的迹象，科尔曼医生
Tests with the ship's equipment shows no signs of internal radiation damage, Doctor Coleman.
莱斯特博士的工作人员在昏迷和临死前不是变得神志不清了吗？
Didn't Dr. Lester's staff become delirious before they went off and died?
是的，舰长，是的
Yes, Captain. Yes.
莱斯特博士可能是被相位枪击晕的
Dr. Lester could be suffering from a phaser stun
根据我对症状的观察，吉姆
as far as the symptoms I can detect, Jim.
科尔曼医生，麦考伊医生在企业号上
Docotr Coleman, Docotr McCoy has had a great deal of experience
有过大量的辐射暴露经验
with radiation exposure on board the Enterprise.
我以他的意见为指导
I am guided by his opinion.
莱斯特博士和她的工作人员在我的监督下已经两年了
Dr. Lester and her staff have been under my supervision for two years now.
如果你不听我的建议
If you don't follow my recommendations,
她的健康或死亡将是你的责任
responsibility for her health or her death will be yours.
麦考伊医生，抱歉
Doctor McCoy, I'm sorry,
我要把你从病例中移出，把它交给科尔曼医生
but I'm going to have to take you off the case and turn it over to Doctor Coleman.
你不能这样做！
You can't do this!
在这艘船上，我的医疗权是最大的
On this ship my medical authority is final!
科尔曼医生想承担全部责任，让他来吧
Doctor Coleman wants to assume the full responsibility. Let him do it.
我不允许的
I won't allow it.
就这么定了！
It's done!
科尔曼医生，你的病人
Docotr Coleman, your patient.
科尔曼医生，你不应该用镇静剂让病人休息吗？
Doctor Coleman, didn't you suggest a sedation to rest the patient?
是的，舰长
Yes, Captain.
没有必要，吉姆，你没看到她正在苏醒吗？
It's not necessary, Jim. Can't you see she's coming around?
科尔曼医生
Docotr Coleman.
护士，注射镇静剂
Nurse, administer the sedative.
现在用镇静剂并不明智，舰长
A sedative is not wise at this time, Captain.
查佩尔护士，这是命令
Nurse Chapel, you have your orders.
查佩尔护士，按照说明操作
Nurse Chapel, follow your instructions.
哦，不，我真的在失去弃企业号的指挥权吗？
Oh no. Am I really losing command of the Enterprise?
不，哦，不，噩梦，噩梦
No. Oh, no. Bad dream. Bad dream.
[柯克]詹姆斯·柯克正在珍妮丝·莱斯特的身体中恢复知觉
[KIRK] James Kirk is returning to consciousness in the body of Janice Lester.
企业号正在前往下一个任务
The Enterprise is proceeding to its next mission,
按照我接过指挥前设定的航线
on the course set before I took over command.
现在，我花在研究飞船运作的每一个细节上的多年时间将得到检验
Now the years I spent studying every single detail of the ship's operation will be tested.
有了一点经验，我就不会被怀疑了
With a little experience, I will be invulnerable to suspicion.
我终于得到我该得的了
At last I attain what is my just due.
星舰的指挥权
Command of a starship.
几个月的准备工作现在终于取得了成果
All the months of preparation now come to fruition.
航线，契科夫先生
Course, Mr. Chekov.
127，标记8
127, mark 8.
苏鲁先生，将速度设置为曲速2级
Mr. Sulu, set speed at warp factor 2.
曲速2级，长官
Warp factor 2, sir.
契科夫先生，绘制一条去贝尼西亚殖民地的航线
Mr. Chekov, plot a course for the Benecia Colony.
直达贝尼西亚的航线，373，标记8
Direct course to Benecia, 373, mark 8.
以我们现在的速度到殖民地还要多久？
How long to the colony at our present speed?
48小时，长官
48 hours, sir.
苏鲁先生，设定到殖民地的航线
Mr. Sulu, set course for the colony.
373，标记8
373, mark 8.
是，长官，373标记8
Aye, sir. 373 mark 8.
舰长，这将耽搁我们在御夫座β的工作
Captain, that will delay our work at Beta Aurigae.
意味着要逆转航线
It means reversing course.
是的，没办法
Yes, it can't be helped.
我们必须把莱斯特医生带到可以接受治疗的地方
We must take Dr. Lester to a place where she can be treated.
我可以指出星际基地2在直达我们目的地的航线上吗？
May I point out that Starbase 2 is on the direct route to our destination?
到星际基地2还要多久？
How long to Starbase 2?
72小时，舰长
72 hours, Captain.
多24小时太久了
That's 24 hours too long.
莱斯特博士的病情越来越严重
Dr. Lester's condition is increasingly serious.
继续当前的航线
Continue present course.
是，长官
Aye, sir.
长官，如果诊断莱斯特医生的病是关键问题
Sir, if the diagnosis of Dr. Lester's illness is the critical problem,
那么贝尼西亚殖民地绝对不适合她
then the Benecia Colony is definitely not the place for her.
他们的医疗设施非常简陋
Their medical facilities are the most primitive.
他们必须得提供服务
They will have to serve.
星际基地2设施非常完善
Starbase 2 is fully equipped
而且配备必要的专家
and staffed with the necessary specialists
能确定博士到底出了什么问题
to determine exactly what is wrong with the doctor.
这对你的决定不重要吗？
Is that not crucial to your decision?
谢谢，史波克先生
Thank you, Mr. Spock.
但如果莱斯特博士死了，这些设施毫无用处
But the facilities will be of little use if Dr. Lester's dead.
时间就是生命，继续当前航线
Time is of the essence. Continue present course.
以最大速度，星际基地2仍然可以应付紧急情况
At maximum speed, Starbase 2 would still meet the emergency.
舰长，我要通知星际舰队指挥部计划改变吗？
Captain, shall I advise Starfleet Command of the change of plan?
没有下令改变计划，上尉
No change of plan has been ordered, Lieutenant.
只是我们要稍微迟一点到达御夫座β
Our arrival at Beta Aurigae will merely be delayed.
我们对该双星系统的引力研究不会受到影响
Our gravitational studies of that binary system will not suffer,
而且也许能挽救一个人的生命!
and a life may be saved!
这对企业号来说并不是不寻常的程序
That is not unusual procedure for the Enterprise.
长官，我认为必须通知星际舰队
Sir, I believe Starfleet will have to be notified
我们与星舰波将金号的会合不会如期进行
that our rendezvous with the starship Potemkin will not take place as scheduled.
史波克先生，如果你专注于你负责的领域
Mr. Spock, if you'd concentrate on the areas for which you are responsible,
星际舰队司令部早就知道了
Starfleet Command would've been informed already.
由于这些事务通常由舰长直接与星际舰队处理
Since the captain usually deals directly with Starfleet in these matters,
我认为我的建议可能会被视为干涉
I assumed that my suggestions might be deemed interference.
将延迟告知星际舰队，上尉
Inform Starfleet of the delay, Lieutenant.
是，长官
Aye, sir.
继续当前航线
Continue present course.
将速度提高到曲速6级
Increase speed to warp factor 6.
我的记录可以为我作证
I'll let my record speak for me.
你为什么这么生气？
Why are you being so defensive?
我把你从病例中移出，并不表示批评你
There's no implied criticism of you in my order to remove you from the case.
这不是我在这里的原因
That is not the reason I'm here.
我在这里是因为科尔曼医生的记录表明他无能
I'm here because Doctor Coleman's record states that he's incompetent.
那是你个人的看法
That's the opinion of an individual.
不，那是星舰指挥部的看法
No, sir. That is the opinion of Starfleet Command.
我向他们核实了
I checked with them.
科尔曼医生因管理无能
Docotr Coleman was removed from his post
而被解除其船上首席医疗官的职务
as Chief Medical Officer of his ship for administrative incompetence.
这里不需要管理职责
There are no administrative duties required here.
也不需要公然的医疗事故
As well as flagrant medical blunders.
晋升和降职可能是政治操纵，你知道的，老骨头
Promotions and demotions can be politically maneuvered. You know that, Bones.
在星际舰队总部不可能，舰长！
Not in Starfleet Headquarters, Captain!
当然在军医署也不可能
And certainly not in the Surgeon General's office.
恐怕命令就是如此
I'm afraid the order will have to stand.
我只能说科尔曼医生的经历和星球上发生的事
I can only say that Doctor Coleman's experience with what happened on the planet
必须是这里的决定因素
had to be the deciding factor here.
我相信你能意识到这一点
I'm sure that you can appreciate that.
我意识到了你要做出决定的事实
I appreciate the fact that you had a decision to make.
我现在也要做个决定，吉姆
I also find myself in that position now, Jim,
我要你来报到做个检查
and I'm asking you to report for an examination.
为什么？你的依据是什么？
Why? What do you base that on?
出现了情绪不稳定和不稳定的心理态度
Development of emotional instability and erratic mental attitudes
自从从那个星球回来后
since returning from that planet.
你的指控永远不会成立
You'll never make that charge stick.
任何傻瓜都能看出你为什么要这样做
Any fool can see why you're doing this.
我会让星际舰队指挥部来判断我的动机
I'll let Starfleet Command be the judge of my motives.
我不会服从这种小小的报复行为
I won't submit to this petty search for revenge!
但你要服从星际舰队的规定
But you will submit to Starfleet regulations,
他们说船上的外科医生需要全面检查
and they state that the ship's surgeon will require full examination
任何他怀疑的船员，包括舰长
of any crew member that he has doubts about, including the captain.
[通讯器发出哔哔声]
[COMMUNICATOR BLEEPS]
我是柯克舰长
Captain Kirk here.
我是苏鲁，舰长
Sulu here, Captain.
星际舰队指挥部要求提供延误的更多详细信息
Starfleet Command is requesting additional details on the delay.
我马上到
I'll be right there.
脉搏压…
Pulse pressure ...
…血量，身体机能正常，那我为什么在这里？
...blood count, all body functions normal, then why am I here?
麦考伊医生？
Doctor McCoy?
麦考伊医生…
Doctor McCoy ...
你最好安静一点
Quiet would be best for you.
麦考伊医生呢？
Where's Doctor McCoy?
现在是我负责
I'm in charge now.
马上带麦考伊医生来！
Bring Doctor McCoy at once!
他在这艘船上掌管医疗
He is in command of medicine on this ship.
他被柯克舰长从你的病例中移出了
He was taken off your case by Captain Kirk.
被柯克舰长？
By Captain Kirk?
这样做是为了保护你自己，莱斯特博士
It was done for your own protection, Dr. Lester.
我不是珍妮丝·莱斯特！她把我变成了这样！
I am not Janice Lester! She did this to me!
现在我怎样才能让你明白？
Now how can I make you understand?
珍妮丝的嫉妒、仇恨和野心把她自己逼疯了
Janice has driven herself mad with jealousy, hatred and ambition.
查佩尔护士，马上让史波克先生和麦考伊医生来我这儿
Nurse Chapel, bring Mr. Spock and Doctor McCoy to me at once.
现在他们必须相信我不是珍妮丝·莱斯特
Now they must believe I am not Janice Lester.
我被囚禁在她的身体里，但我不是珍妮丝·莱斯特
I am imprisoned in her body, but I am not Janice Lester.
她正遭受成为柯克舰长的错觉
She is suffering from the delusion of being Captain Kirk.
我不是珍妮丝莱斯特！
I am not Janice Lester!
这种偏执过去六个月一直在发展
The paranoia has been developing for the past six months.
辐射似乎加剧了它
The radiation seems to have intensified it.
她必须保持镇静
She must be kept sedated.
我要准备一种温和的镇静剂吗，医生？
Shall prepare a mild sedative, Doctor?
当然
Of course.
你疯了，莱斯特博士
You are insane, Dr. Lester.
[柯克]舰长日志，星历未知
[KIRK] Captain's log, stardate unknown.
我忘记了时间
I have lost track of time.
我仍然被囚禁在一个陌生的身体里
I am still held captive in a strange body
并与我所有的船员分开
and separated from all my crew.
在你听来我之前一定很疯狂
I must have sounded quite mad to you before.
你的经历会让我们大多数人都崩溃
What you've been through would break most of us.
我现在已经好了
Well, I'll be all right now.
我能见见你的麦考伊医生吗？
Could I see your Doctor McCoy?
恐怕这违反了科尔曼医生的命令
I'm afraid that's against Doctor Coleman's orders.
哦，允许那个非常善良的史波克先生来访吗？
Oh. Is a visit by that very kind Mr. Spock to be allowed?
也许在我们到达贝尼西亚殖民地之前能安排
Perhaps that can be arranged before we reach the Benecia Colony.
贝尼西亚殖民地？
The Benecia Colony?
企业号不是要在御夫座β与波将金号会合吗？
But isn't the Enterprise going to rendezvous with the Potemkin at Beta Aurigae?
嗯，首先我们得让你在贝尼西亚疗养
Well, first we have to let you recuperate at Benecia.
喝一点，你会舒服一些
You'll feel better if you have a little.
嗯，我会试试的，谢谢
Well, I'll try. Thank you.
哦，很好喝，谢谢
Oh, it is good. Thank you.
我可以慢慢喝完吗，查佩尔护士？
Could I finish it slowly, Nurse Chapel?
呃…
Well ...
我保证我会乖乖的
I promise I'll be good.
好，我马上就回来
Well, I'll be right back.
我很高兴你感觉好多了
I'm glad you're feeling so much better.
这些测试应该能帮助我查明吉姆生病的原因
These tests should help me pinpoint the cause of Jim's illness.
很好，舰长行为异常的消息正在船上传播
Good. Knowledge of the captain's aberrant behaviour is spreading through the ship.
船员越来越紧张
The crew is becoming increasingly tense.
没错，我最担心的
Yes, well what worries me most
是吉姆似乎完全没有意识到他有问题
is that Jim seems completely unaware something is wrong with him.
我们必须让他意识到已经发生了严重的事情
We've got to make him realize that something serious is happening
在开始治疗之前
before treatment can even begin.
我恐怕希望渺茫，医生
I'm afraid that is a forlorn hope, Doctor.
这种疾病似乎主要是精神上的
The illness appears to be primarily mental.
我们中的一个人应该能说服他，我…
Well, one of us should be able to get to him. I ...
我不知道，我一直在寻找一种方法
I don't know. I keep looking for an approach,
但疾病扩散的速度使其变得加倍困难
but the speed at which the illness has traveled makes it doubly difficult.
也许应该提醒军医署
Perhaps the Surgeon General's office should be alerted.
你了解总部的，史波克
You know headquarters, Spock.
他们只对特定测试的结果感兴趣
They're only interested in results of specific tests.
目前为止我们只能提供意见
So far all we have to offer are our opinions.
你确定以舰长现在的精神状态他会服从你的命令吗？
Are you sure that the captain will comply with your order in his present state of mind?
如有必要我会使用我的医疗权力强制执行
I'll use my medical authority to enforce it if necessary.
医生，我们必须如履薄冰
Doctor, we are treading on very thin ground.
诸如此类的行为可能会被误解
Actions such as these might be misinterpreted.
那么就是吧
Well, then, so be it.
我们的责任很明确
Our responsibility is clear.
不管在那个星球上舰长发生了什么
Whatever happened to the captain on that planet
一定是在他和莱斯特博士单独相处的短时间内发生的
must've taken place in the short space of time that he was alone with Dr. Lester.
与她的谈话可能会有所启发
Perhaps a conversation with her might shed some light.
嗯，这值得一试
Well, it's worth a try.
要不我检查吉姆时，你试着去找莱斯特医生
Why don't you try to get to Dr. Lester while I examine Jim.
好，先生们，我来了，医生
Well, gentlemen. I'm here, Doctor.
史波克，老骨头，帮帮我
Spock, Bones, help me.
别让他们把我关起来和你们分开
Don't let them lock me away from you.
我得和你们谈谈
I've got to talk to you.
吉姆！
Jim!
她可能杀了人
She might have killed someone.
把她隔离在她房间
Put her in isolation in her room.
24小时看守
Maintain a 24-hour watch.
任何人，禁止任何人未经我允许就和她说话
No one, absolutely no one, is to talk to her without my permission！
是，长官
Yes, sir.
舰长
Captain
博士怎么样？
How is the doctor?
她很快恢复了知觉
She regained consciousness very quickly.
很好，我有几个问题要问她
Good. I have questions to ask her.
是舰长命令的吗，长官？
Did the captain order it, sir?
为什么他要命令？
Why should he?
我有问题要问，因此是我在下命令，上尉
They are my questions, therefore I am ordering it, Lieutenant.
舰长说禁止任何人和莱斯特博士说话
The captain said no one is allowed to speak to Dr. Lester.
以前这种命令包括他的高级军官吗？
Has such an order ever included his senior officers?
没有，长官
No, sir.
史波克先生，我想舰长的意思是应该有一个警卫在场
Mr. Spock, I think the captain meant that a guard should be present.
当然可以，上尉
By all means, Lieutenant.
够了，够了
That's enough. That's enough.
你的心脏还能跳很久，舰长
Your heart will last forever, Captain.
其他部分怎么样？
How am I otherwise?
像往常一样非常健康
In the pink as usual.
肝、肾、血细胞计数、代谢率、
Liver, kidney, blood count, metabolic rate,
所有功能，甚至你的腺体
everything, even your glands,
都以通常的正常效率峰值运行
functioning at their usual, normal peak of efficiency.
好的，我希望你和我一样满意
Good. I hope you're as pleased about it as I am.
慢点穿上
Don't get dressed yet.
你说我身体很好
You said I was in perfect condition.
身体上
Physically.
我认为没必要进行另一个测试
I don't think another test is necessary.
罗比阿尼皮肤视觉是至关重要的
The Robbiani dermal-optic is crucial.
它显示了基本的情绪结构
It reveals the basic emotional structure.
你以前测过一次
You had one once before.
现在我需要再测一次来与之前的测试进行比较
Now I need another one to compare with that previous test.
你对颜色波长的皮肤视觉反应
There should be no change in your dermal-optic reactions
应该没有变化
to the color wavelengths.
过来，舰长
Over here, Captain.
借助机械装置完成生命实体转移？
Complete life-entity transfer with the aid of a mechanical device?
是的，一定是这样的
Yes, that's what it must've been.
据我所知，这样的完全转移从未完全成功地完成过
To my knowledge, such total transfer has never been accomplished with complete success
在银河系的任何地方
anywhere in the galaxy.
很久以前在加缪二上完成并被遗忘了
It was accomplished and forgotten long ago on Camus II.
我就是一个活生生的例子
I'm a living example.
那是你的一面之辞
That is your claim.
迄今为止，没有得到任何…外部证据的证实
As yet it is unsubstantiated by any ... external evidence,
或客观测试
or objective tests.
然而我说的是实话，史波克
Nevertheless, Spock, it is the truth I'm speaking.
现在放下你的手臂，睁开你的眼睛
Now lower your arms and open your eyes.
此刻，麦考伊医生正在检查
At this moment, Doctor McCoy is examining
舰长的精神变化
the captain for psychological changes.
如果发现任何事实
If any facts are uncovered,
那将是可以接受的证据
that would be acceptable evidence.
星际舰队指挥部和企业号的船员
The only kind which is acceptable to Starfleet Command
唯一可以接受的证据
and to the crew of the Enterprise.
史波克，当我被困在索利安星区的间隙中时
Spock, when I was caught in the interspace of the Tholian Sector,
你冒着你和企业号的安危让我回来
you risked your life and the Enterprise to get me back.
现在帮我回去
Help me get back now.
当米纳拉的维恩人要求我们让老骨头死的时候
When the Vians of Minara demanded that we let Bones die,
我们没有允许
we didn't permit it.
没错，舰长没有
That is true. The captain did not.
但是，那些事件已被记录下来
However, those events have been recorded.
这些事可能为你所知
They could have become known to you.
你和舰长的关系比宇宙中任何人都亲近
You are closer to the captain than anyone in the universe.
你知道他的想法
You know his thoughts.
你的心灵感应现在告诉你什么？
What does your telepathic mind tell you now?
我相信你
I believe you.
然而，我相信并不是可以接受的证据
However, my belief is not acceptable evidence.
证据必须是真实的
Evidence must be factual.
麦考伊医生也许能上帮忙
Doctor McCoy may be of help.
跟我来
Come with me.
对不起，长官，但莱斯特博士不能离开这里
I'm sorry, sir, but Dr. Lester cannot leave here.
那你对测试结果满意吗？
Well, are you satisfied with the results of the tests?
没有明确证据表明任何疾病
There is no positive evidence of any disorder.
你在让我违反舰长的命令
You're asking me to violate the captain's orders.
他不是舰长
He is not the captain.
你和她一样疯
You're as mad as she is.
你要立刻离开这里，我服从命令
You're to leave here at once. I follow orders.
当然，上尉，我们都必须尽自己的职责
Certainly, Lieutenant. We all must do our duty.
警卫！
Security guard!
没有难受的感觉，老骨头
No hard feelings, Bones.
你的活儿一如既往细致优秀
You did your usual thorough, good job.
我相信一切都会好起来的
I'm sure everything's going to be all right.
[哔哔]
[BLEEPING]
男人[通过对讲机]柯克舰长？
MAN [OVER INTERCOM] Captain Kirk?
我是柯克舰长
Captain Kirk here.
莱斯特博士试图逃脱
Escape attempt by Dr. Lester.
柯克舰长呼叫警卫
Captain Kirk to security.
立刻去莱斯特博士房间
On the double to Dr. Lester's room.
没问题，少尉，一切都在控制之中
It's quite all right, Ensign. Everything is under control.
相位枪
Phasers.
不要有有任何肢体暴力行为…长官
A repetition of your physical violence is not called for ... sir.
我不会有身体上的反抗
No physical resistance will be offered.
注意，所有人员
Attention, all personnel.
大副史波克已被逮捕
First Officer Spock has been placed under arrest.
他与莱斯特博士密谋从你们的舰长手中接管这艘船
He has conspired with Dr. Lester to take over the ship from your captain.
将立即召开听证会审议
A hearing will be immediately convened to consider the charges and specifications
军事法庭对…叛变的指控和量刑
of a general court martial on the charge ... of mutiny.
[珍妮丝]舰长日志，星历5930.3
[JANICE] Captain's log, stardate 5930.3.
麦考伊医生的检查结果给了我十足的信心
The results of Doctor McCoy's examination have given me complete confidence in myself.
我的恐惧已经消失
My fears are past.
我将作为舰长自由发挥舰长职能
I shall function freely as the captain.
事实上，我就是企业号的舰长
I am captain of the Enterprise, in fact.
当然，你必须有更多的东西才能继续
Surely you must have more than that to go on.
我已经陈述了我的证据
I have stated my evidence.
与詹姆斯·T·柯克舰长的心灵感应交流
Telepathic communication with the mind of Captain James T. Kirk.
你的证据是完全主观的
Your evidence is completely subjective.
我们必须有可以公开查验的证据
We have to have evidence that we can examine out in the open.
你已经有了大量的证据
You've had great deal of evidence,
除了主要证人的
except that of the chief witness.
本应是这次调查的真正对象的人
The one who should be the real subject of this investigation
被锁起来，并处于隔离状态
is kept locked away and in isolation.
为什么，舰长？
Why, Captain?
她是个危险的疯子，我们已经看到了证据
She's dangerously insane. We've seen the evidence.
她只对你的权力构成危险，长官
She is dangerous only to your authority, sir.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
史波克先生，我的权力是星际舰队指挥部授予我的
Mr. Spock, my authority has been given to me by Starfleet Command,
只有最高权力机构才能把它拿走
and only that high authority can take it away.
证人，长官，带证人上来
The witness, sir. Bring on the witness.
让你的军官提出问题
Let your officers put the questions.
莱姆里先生，带珍妮丝·莱斯特博士带来这里
Mr. Lemli, have Dr. Janice Lester brought here.
是，长官
Aye, sir.
麦考伊医生
Doctor McCoy,
当史波克先生忙于他雄心勃勃的阴谋时，你在做什么？
while Mr. Spock was busy with his ambitious plot, what were you doing?
检查你
Examining you.
哦，是的，你深切地关心我的
Oh, yes. You were deeply concerned about my
健康，情绪和身体，自从离开加缪二之后
health, emotional and physical, since leaving Camus Two.
对吗？
Is that correct?
是的，没错
Yes, that's correct.
你没有试图杀死我，而是在寻找帮助我的方法
Instead of trying to destroy me, you were searching for ways to help me.
麦考伊医生，为了记录在案
Doctor McCoy, for the record,
你会告诉法庭你的检查结果吗？
will you tell the court your findings?
舰长处于最佳的身体状态
The captain is in the best of physical condition.
他的情绪和精神状态
His emotional and mental state
与他担任企业号指挥的时候相当
is comparable to the time that he assumed command of the Enterprise.
谢谢，麦考伊医生
Thank you, Doctor McCoy.
史波克先生，你知道麦考伊医生的检查结果吗？
Mr. Spock, were you aware of Doctor McCoy's findings?
我现在知道了
I know them now.
那你现在有什么要说的？
And what have you to say now?
我很失望和深深地担心
I am disappointed and deeply concerned
没有客观证据支持我的立场
that there is no objective evidence to support my position.
到目前为止
So far.
科尔曼医生，如果这里需要你，我们会传唤你
Docotr Coleman, if you're required here, we'll call you.
无疑我们感谢你的到来
We certainly appreciate your being here.
每个人都深深地意识到你受到了
Everyone is deeply aware that you have been subjected to
过度的情绪压力
inordinate emotional stress.
我们希望避免任何进一步的压力
We had hoped to avoid any further stress,
但史波克先生不同意
but Mr. Spock disagrees.
他认为你的证词很重要
It is his opinion that your testimony is important
在确定他的论据的真假时
in determining the merits of his case.
由于我们只对做出公正的决定感兴趣
And since we are solely interested in arriving at a just decision,
我将不得不再问你几个问题
I'm going to have to ask you a few more questions.
我会尽量不惹恼你
I'll try not to upset you.
你声称…
You claim that ...
你是詹姆斯·T·柯克舰长？
that you are Captain James T. Kirk?
不，我不是柯克舰长
No. I am not Captain Kirk.
这是非常明显的
That is very apparent.
我声称使詹姆斯·柯克成为一个对他自己来说很特殊的生命体的东西
I claim that whatever it is that makes James Kirk a living being special to himself
被关在这里在这具身体里
is being held here in this body.
哦，那根据我的理解
Oh. Well. However, as I understand it,
我是珍妮丝·莱斯特博士
I am Dr. Janice Lester.
[全体笑]
[ALL LAUGH]
很聪明，但我没这么说
That's very clever, but I didn't say it.
我说的是，詹妮丝·莱斯特博士正在使用詹姆斯·柯克的身体
I said, the body of James Kirk is being used by Dr. Janice Lester.
不知为何我忽略了微妙的不同
A subtlety that somehow escapes me.
我假设这个转换是通过双方协议达成的
I assume that this switch was arrived at by mutual agreement.
不，是莱斯特博士的暴力袭击造成的
No. It was brought about by a violent attack by Dr. Lester
并使用她在加缪二上发现的设备
and the use of equipment she discovered on Camus II.
这位女士对柯克舰长施暴？
Violence by the lady, perpetrated on Captain Kirk?
我请参会人员看看珍妮丝·莱斯特博士
I ask the assembled personnel to look at Dr. Janice Lester
并想象那个历史性的时刻
and visualize that historic moment.
你能，你能告诉我珍妮丝·莱斯特博士为什么
Can you, can you tell me why Dr. Janice Lester
会同意这种荒唐的交换吗？
would agree to this ludicrous exchange?
能，为了获得她渴望的力量
Yes. To get the power she craved.
为了获得一个以她的秉性和训练不应该得到的职位
To attain a position she doesn't merit by temperament or training.
而且，最重要的是，她想谋杀詹姆斯·柯克
And, most of all, she wanted to murder James Kirk,
一个曾经爱过她的男人
a man who once loved her.
但她对自己的女性身份的强烈憎恨使她无法继续生活
But her intense hatred of her own womanhood made life with her impossible.
你有目击者吗？一个就够了
Are you prepared with witnesses? One will do.
长官，只有一个问题
Sir, there is only one issue here.
生命实体转移的故事可信吗？
Is the story of life-entity transfer believable?
这班船员去过银河系的很多地方
This crew has been to many places in the galaxy.
目睹过很多奇怪的事件
They've been witness to many strange events.
他们受过训练，知道看似不可能的事情往往是可能的
They are trained to know that what seems to be impossible often is possible,
鉴于对这一现象的科学分析
given the scientific analysis of the phenomenon.
史波克先生，你听说过类似珍妮丝·莱斯特博士描述的案例吗？
Mr. Spock, have you ever heard of a case such as described by Dr. Janice Lester?
不确切地说，没有
Not precisely, no.
假设你的看法是正确的
Assuming that you are correct in your belief,
你希望星际舰队指挥部安排这个呃…这个呃…人
do you expect Starfleet Command to place this er ... this er ... person
指挥企业号吗？
in command of the Enterprise?
我只希望揭露真相
I expect only to reveal the truth.
随着真相揭开，我不是真的舰长
And with the truth revealed, that I am not really the captain,
并且知道她不会被允许担任舰长
and knowing that she would not be allowed to serve as the captain,
那你就会是舰长！这是肯定的！
then you would be the captain! It is inevitable!
史波克，史波克，放弃吧！
Spock. Spock, give it up!
回归企业号大家庭，所有指控都将被撤销
Return to the Enterprise family. All charges will be dropped
以及在加缪二上暂时战胜了我们所有人的疯狂
and the madness that temporarily overcame all of us on Camus II
会褪色并被遗忘
will fade and be forgotten.
莱斯特博士会怎样？
And what will become of Dr. Lester?
莱斯特博士将得到永久照看
Dr. Lester will be cared for always.
这是我过去欠她的责任
It is a debt and a responsibility I owe her from the past.
不，长官，我不会撤回我提出的任何指控
No, sir, I shall not withdraw a single charge that I have made.
你不是柯克舰长
You are not Captain Kirk.
你残忍地占用了他的躯体
You have ruthlessly appropriated his body,
但你内在的生命实体不是柯克舰长的
but the life entity within you is not that of Captain Kirk.
企业号不应该由你由你掌管
You do not belong in charge of the Enterprise
我将尽我所能反抗你
and I shall do everything in my power against you.
丽萨上尉，回放史波克先生长篇大论的最后两句话
Lieutenant Lysa, play back those last two sentences from Mr. Spock's tirade.
企业号不应该由你由你掌管
You do not belong in charge of the Enterprise
我将尽我所能反抗你
and I shall do everything in my power against you.
你听到了你记录在案的陈述
You heard the statements placed into the record by you.
你知道这些话的性质吗？
Do you understand the nature of it?
我知道，而且我坚持这样做
I do. And I stand by it.
是叛变！蓄意、报复、疯狂的叛变！
It is mutiny! Deliberate, vindictive, insane at its base!
但已经指控了叛变，这是怂恿叛变
But mutiny is charged, and encouragement to mutiny.
麦考伊医生，斯科特先生，你们听到了！
Doctor McCoy, Mr. Scott, you heard it!
基于这些陈述，用作为企业号舰长赋予我的权力
On the basis of these statements, I call for an immediate vote,
我呼吁立即投票
by the powers granted to me as captain of the Enterprise.
宣布休会，随后进行表决
A recess is declared, to be followed by a vote.
是，长官，在我们的首席证人面前立即投票
Yes, sir. An immediate vote before our chief witness
能让她死在某个不起眼的星球上，让真相和她一起被掩埋
can be left to die on some obscure planet with the truth locked away inside of her.
安静！你要安静！
Silence! You will be silent!
已宣布休会，不再进行交叉讨论
A recess has been declared. There will be no cross-discussion.
当我回来时，我们将就叛变的指控进行表决
When I return, we will vote on the charge of mutiny.
此处提供的证据是你做出决定的唯一依据
The evidence presented here is the only basis of your decision.
斯科提
Scotty.
医生
Doctor.
我见过舰长发烧，生病
I've seen the captain feverish, sick,
醉酒，神志不清，害怕，喜出望外，火冒三丈
drunk, delirious, terrified, overjoyed, boiling mad.
但到目前为止，我从未见过他气急败坏地红着脸
But up to now I have never seen him red-faced with hysteria.
我知道我要怎么投票了
I know how I'm going to vote.
我和史波克已经经历过这种情况了
I've been through this with Spock.
他不讲科学，你也不讲科学
He's not being scientific and neither are you.
可能不科学
It may not be scientific,
但如果史波克先生认为它是这样的，那么它就是合乎逻辑的
but if Mr. Spock thinks it happened, then it must be logical.
你不认为我知道吗？
Don't you think I know that?
我的测试表明舰长没有任何问题
My tests show there's nothing wrong with the captain.
这是星际舰队唯一会感兴趣的事实
Now that's the only fact Starfleet's going to be interested in.
总部有总部的问题，我们有我们的问题
Headquarters has its problems, and we have ours.
而现在企业号舰长就是我们的问题
And right now the captain of the Enterprise is our problem.
他们将在几分钟内召集投票
They're going to call for the vote in a few minutes.
让我提出最后一个问题
Let me put one last question.
假设你和我一起投票支持史波克
Suppose you vote with me in favor of Spock.
那意味着二票对一票，史波克是无罪的
That means two votes to one and Spock is free.
你觉得舰长会怎么做？
What do you think the captain will do?
我不知道
I don't know.
是的，你知道的，是不是
Aye, you know, all right.
他会无法接受
It'll stick in his craw.
他永远不会接受
He'll never accept it.
我们还不知道
We don't know that.
我告诉你他不会接受
I tell you, he won't.
然后，医生，那就是我们反对他的时候了
Then, Doctor, that's the time we move against him.
我们将不得不接管这艘船
We'll have to take over the ship.
我们在谈论叛变，斯科提
We're talking about mutiny, Scotty.
是的
Aye.
你准备好投票了吗？
Are you ready for the vote?
是的，我准备好投票了
Yes. I'm ready for the vote.
播放走廊里的谈话录音
Play the tapes of the conversation in the corridor.
是，长官
Aye, sir.
然后就是我们反对他的时候了
Then's the time we move against him.
我们将不得不接管这艘船
We'll have to take over the ship.
我们正在谈论叛变，斯科提
We're talking about mutiny, Scotty.
是的
Aye.
你准备好投票了吗？
Are you ready for the vote?
够了，我们知道我们说了什么
That's enough. We know what was said.
足够判你与叛变者共谋
Enough to convict you of conspiracy with mutineers.
你被指控这个罪名
And you're so charged.
判决，死刑
The sentence, death.
莱姆里先生
Mr. Lemli.
星际舰队明确禁止死刑
Starfleet expressly forbids the death penalty.
我所有的高级官员都反对我？
All my senior officers turning against me?
死刑是禁止的
The death penalty is forbidden.
只有一个例外
There's only one exception.
第4号通令
General Order 4.
企业号上还没有官员违反过该命令
It has not been violated by any officer on the Enterprise.
我来负责
I am responsible.
处决将立即执行，去你们的岗位上
The execution will be immediate. Go to your posts.
去你们的岗位上
Go to your posts.
莱姆里先生，带他们去禁闭室
Mr. Lemli, take them to the brig.
准备处决
Prepare for execution.
走啊！
Go on!
舰长一定是疯了
The captain really must be going mad,
如果他认为他能逃过处决
if he thinks he can get away with an execution.
柯克舰长即使疯了也不会下令处决
Captain Kirk wouldn't order an execution even if he were going mad.
那不可能是舰长
That cannot be the captain.
他是谁有什么区别？
What difference does it make who he is?
我们要允许执行处决吗？
Are we going to allow an execution to take place?
如果警卫支持他，我们要如何对抗他？
If security backs him up, how will we fight him?
我将以各种方式和方法与他们战斗
I'll fight them every way and any way I can.
丽萨上尉，将我的决定通知所有部门
Lieutenant Lysa, inform all sectors of my decision.
让每个部门派一名代表去机库甲板的处决地点
Have each section send a representative to the place of execution on the hangar deck.
契科夫先生，离贝尼西亚殖民地有多远？
Mr. Chekov, how far to the Benecia Colony?
正在进入扫描范围
Coming within scanning range.
绘制轨道坐标
Plot coordinates for orbit.
苏鲁先生，完成轨道后锁定坐标
Mr. Sulu, lock into coordinates as soon as orbit is accomplished.
拘留将在贝尼西亚进行
Internment will take place on Benicia.
你们听到我的命令了！
You have received your orders!
你们要服从我的命令！
You will obey my orders!
你们将被指控叛变
You will be charged with mutiny.
你会服从我的命令或者…或者…
You will obey my orders or ... or ...
有那么一刻我…我以为我在舰桥上
For a moment I ... I thought I was up on the bridge.
也许你确实在
Perhaps you were.
也就是说转移是可能被打破的
Then it's possible the transference can be broken.
如果再次发生，我会争取留在那
Well, if it happens again, I'll fight to stay there.
你属于舰桥
The bridge is where you belong.
为了实现这一目标
To accomplish that,
我们每个人都必须准备好抓住任何机会
each of us must be ready to seize any opportunity
冲出这里进行攻击
to break out of here and attack.
亚瑟，转移正在变弱
Arthur, the transference is weakening.
发生了什么？
What happened?
有那么一会儿，我发现自己和囚犯在一起​​
For a moment, I found myself back with the prisoners.
我不要再回去做珍妮丝·莱斯特了
I will not go back to being Janice Lester.
你必须帮我阻止它
You must help me prevent it.
阻止转移的唯一方法是让珍妮丝·莱斯特死
The only way to prevent the transference is by the death of Janice Lester.
你必须执行处决
You must carry out the execution.
我不能，我不能
I can't. I can't.
船员们正在叛变
The crew is in mutiny.
你必须帮我杀了她
You must kill her for me.
我已经为你做了其他一切事情
I have done everything else for you.
但我不会为你杀人
But I will not murder for you.
那就为你自己做
Then do it for yourself.
如果柯克不死，我们都会被揭露为凶手
If Kirk doesn't die, we'll both be exposed as murderers.
你有其他选择吗？
Does that give you any choice?
剂量应该是加倍致命的
The dosage should be doubly lethal.
是的
It is.
为了防止更多阴谋，你们将被移到独立牢房
To prevent further conspiracy, you will be removed to separate cells.
如果有任何抵抗，将给你们注射镇静剂，直到你们学会合作
If there's any resistance, you'll be given a sedative until you learn cooperation.
莱斯特博士打头
Dr. Lester will be first.
跟着科尔曼医生
Follow Docotr Coleman.
我可以指出吗，舰长…
May I point out, Captain ...
杀了他！
Kill him!
杀了他，啊啊！
Kill him. Aaah!
我失去了与舰长的联系
I've lost to the captain.
我感觉不到詹姆斯·柯克了！
I've lost to James Kirk!
我要你死！
I want you dead!
我要你死！我要你死…
I want you dead! I want you dead ...
哦，我永远不会成为舰长了
Oh, I'm never going to be the captain.
永远
Never.
你是…你是因为我爱你
You are ... You are as I loved you.
杀了他
Kill him.
你能为她做些什么吗？
Can you do anything for her?
我愿意照顾她
I'd like to take care of her.
当然，跟我来
Of course. Come with me.
我不想毁了她
I didn't want to destroy her.
我相信我们都理解，舰长
I'm sure we all understand that, Captain.
她的生活本可以和任何女人一样丰富
Her life could have been as rich as any woman's,
要是…
if only ...
要是
If only.